guys this looks like a fun one we're
giving some triangles with some angles
this is congruent to this and they give
us the values of these two angles and
they're asking us to solve for x let's
do this if you want to try this on your
own pause it because I'm going to solve
it in three two one for the first step
let's focus on this linear pair right
here I want to find out what is this
other angle combine these form 180
degrees so we know that the question
mark plus 45 will equal 180. that'll be
true if the question mark is 135 so we
know that this angle is 135 degrees next
let's focus on this triangle right here
what is the value of this angle the sum
of the interior angles of a triangle is
always equal to 180 degrees and this
will be true for 30 so we can change
this angle to 30 degrees and now that we
know this 30 degrees we won't need this
135 anymore starting from the vertex of
this angle let's draw out this blue
segment and construct a circle with that
as the radius now let's find where this
circle intersects this let's connect
this intersection point to the center of
our Circle this is another radius of the
circle so it's equal to this segment
right here and now we don't need this
circle anymore next let's focus on this
triangle right here since there are two
sides congruent in this triangle we know
it's an isosceles triangle and the angle
is opposite the congruent sides are also
congruent so we know that this angle
right here is also 30 degrees and now to
find the last angle of the triangle we
can set them all equal to 180 and this
will be true for 120. so this angle
right here is 120 degrees next I want to
find this angle right here and we're
going to use these three angles to get
it this angle plus this angle plus this
angle will all add up to 180 degrees and
this statement will be true for 15. so
we know that this angle right here is 15
degrees next I'm thinking let's focus on
this triangle right here since these
angles are both 15 degrees we know it's
an isosceles triangle and the sides
opposite the congruent angles are also
congruent next let's connect this
intersection point with this vertex
right here now let's focus on our new
triangle to find this angle down here we
need to add the 15 degrees and the 45
degrees to get 60 degrees and now let's
get the last two angles of this triangle
this is another isosceles triangle so we
know that these two angles are congruent
to each other and we also know that if
we add up all three of these angles it's
going to be 180 degrees this will be
true if both of these angles are 60
degrees and now since all three angles
are 60 degrees we know it's an
equilateral triangle so all three sides
are going to be congruent so now from
here I'm interested in this angle right
here so let's focus on these three
angles and find that angle right there
these three angles are also going to add
to 180 degrees and this will be true if
the angle is 90 degrees so let's put one
of those little boxes right there to
show that's 90 degrees for our next step
let's focus on this right triangle right
here it's also an isosceles triangle so
we know that these two angles are going
to be congruent to each other and if we
add up all three of these angles we can
find out that each of these are 45
degree angle let's look at this x
degrees in this 15 degrees let's make
them red we know that the sum of these
two angles will be equal to this larger
angle so we have X plus 15 is equal to
45. so we subtract 15 from both sides we
find that X is equal to 30. and that is
the answer to our question they wanted
us to solve for x so let's clean things
up a little bit and put a box around it
x equals 30 how exciting